<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>$ jekyll serve | Mars, front-end developer.</title>
    <description>Powered by a lady developer</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>LAMP, WordPress, and Forge theming on Ubuntu 14.04</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do a quick post on setting up LAMP, WordPress, then ultimately using Forge for WordPress theming on Ubuntu Trusty 14.04.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than write my own guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll link to a helpful post that guided me through the process of installing LAMP and WordPress locally on Ubuntu 14.04:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-wordpress-on-ubuntu-12-04&quot;&gt;How To Install Wordpress on Ubuntu 12.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the author wrote the guide for 12.04, here&amp;rsquo;s my tip to save you some time and headache:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anywhere /var/www/ is mentioned, use /var/www&lt;strong&gt;/html&lt;/strong&gt;/ instead since that&amp;rsquo;s where Apache sets up sites on 14.04.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, instead of using these commands to grant Apache ownership:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;sudo chown username:www-data /var/www -R
sudo chmod g+w /var/www -R 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;sudo chown username:www-data /var/www/html -R 
sudo chmod g+w /var/www/html -R 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ensures your LAMP setup will work on 14.04. &lt;em&gt;The more you know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though she mentions it, for future reference - all you need to do to grab a copy of the latest WordPress tarball is command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;wget http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding &lt;a href=&quot;http://forge.thethemefoundry.com&quot;&gt;Forge&lt;/a&gt;, I have yet to use it, but I plan to for theming freelance WordPress projects on Linux. It comes equipped with CSS compilers and all the tools needed to produce a neat little WordPress theme file ready for upload. The project hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in a while so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it&amp;rsquo;s still operational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of a better/updated workflow for theming WP on Linux, I&amp;rsquo;d love to know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/09/14/ubuntu-14.04-lamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/09/14/ubuntu-14.04-lamp/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Latest Project > Skreened.com Redesign</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The dev team at Skreened just wrapped up redesign and redevelopment of &lt;a href=&quot;http://skreened.com&quot;&gt;skreened.com&lt;/a&gt;, the e-commerce storefront to thousands of creatively designed and ethically made apparel products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marsadie.github.io/blog/images/skreened-homepage.png&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile-first was the name of the game. It needed to be responsive and look great across mobile devices old and new and among popular browsers, as well as on the big screen. We beat up and tested as much as we could (thanks in part to local coworking space &lt;a href=&quot;http://saltmines.us&quot;&gt;The Salt Mines&lt;/a&gt;) before issuing the new release last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://marsadie.github.io/blog/images/skreened-responsive.png&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role was front-end development and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier to work with such a great team. My own toolkit included Linux (Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty), PHPStorm, Less/CSS, and Git version control (a must for team projects and a system I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to master - no pun intended!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went with the Bootstrap 3 framework. I did a lot of finger-cracking front-end coding including HTML5, CSS3 by way of Less, jQuery, and PHP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the limited amount of time we had to begin and complete this release, and succeeding, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to be a part of Skreened&amp;rsquo;s dev team. It&amp;rsquo;s been a pleasure working with our pixel-perfect UX/UI designer, our savvy backend developer, and our awesome team lead who holds everything together. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t work better together, and I realize that as a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transitioning from freelance to full-time work has been a breeze thanks to Skreened and I was ecstatic to take on such a substantial project from the beginning - redesigning a successful e-commerce website to make it even better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/09/08/skreened-redesign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/09/08/skreened-redesign/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching from GoDaddy/WordPress to GitHub Pages/Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I dumped my remaining GoDaddy hosting account earlier this month and am not really looking to go back. I was paying around $108/year for the dedicated space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress was my CMS of choice for many of my projects. With its plugins and ease of use, it did everything I wanted. Plus, it was easy to code and template, and it felt natural to blog from there. I&amp;rsquo;d been using WordPress since 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, WordPress is sort of clunky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tumblr I could never really get into. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I&amp;rsquo;ve shifted headspace and decided I wanted to try something new, more lightweight (both in terms of price and feel), and more &lt;em&gt;nerdy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://marsadie.github.io/2014/06/13/its-friday-13th/&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;d set up this blog using Jekyll. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted on Github Pages, which is free for Jekyll projects, and accepts custom domains. Can you see where I&amp;rsquo;m going?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github Pages are open source for free users/organizations, which I&amp;rsquo;m not at all concerned about. Sharing is caring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first projects I&amp;rsquo;d like to develop via Github using Jekyll include a nationwide freelance job board (which I had going with WordPress before) - as soon as I learn how to parse an OPML file - and a static beauty blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool Jekyll sites (by lady developers!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenmyers.net&quot;&gt;jenmyers.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://nicoledominguez.com&quot;&gt;nicoledominguez.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info on setting up Jekyll/Github Pages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll &amp;bull; Simple, blog-aware, static sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://24ways.org/2013/get-started-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;Getting Started With GitHub Pages (Plus Bonus Jekyll)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bdunagan.com/2013/11/08/why-i-moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Why I moved from Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href=&quot;http://jbeckwith.com/2013/07/17/wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Switching from Wordpress to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/06/24/game-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/06/24/game-change/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Friday Five 6.20.14</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;{&lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrostweb.com/blog/web/advice-to-new-web-designers/&quot;&gt;How to Land Your First Job as a Web Designer/Developer&lt;/a&gt;} &amp;bull; &lt;em&gt;I landed my first salary position as a web developer this spring and these are great tips. Prove your chops by experience - no fancy degree needed!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{&lt;a href=&quot;http://ostraining.com/blog/coding/bootstrap-right-way/&quot;&gt;Using Bootstrap the Right (Semantic) Way&lt;/a&gt;} &amp;bull; &lt;em&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do ourselves a favor and begin utilizing Less mixins already built into Bootstrap to produce more semantic code, better suited for future updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{&lt;a href=&quot;http://lesscss.org/features/&quot;&gt;Features of the Less language&lt;/a&gt;} &amp;bull; &lt;em&gt;Less can do some pretty stellar things to both empower and simplify your CSS code. Educate yo self.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dypsilon/frontend-dev-bookmarks&quot;&gt;Frontend Dev Bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;} &amp;bull; &lt;em&gt;Too cool. I have this page docked to my desktop at work for hyper accessibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{&lt;a href=&quot;http://ami.responsivedesign.is&quot;&gt;Am I responsive?&lt;/a&gt;} &amp;bull; &lt;em&gt;Well? Are you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/06/20/friday-five/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/06/20/friday-five/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My [Trusty] New Ubuntu install via Chromebook...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The weekend was dedicated to relaxing, spending one day with family and one day alone. Saturday my sister, her children, and I did dinner, then had ice cream. Sunday I took myself to brunch. Too much sashimi thrust me into a midday &lt;del&gt;coma&lt;/del&gt; nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I had some ongoing freelance work to wrap up as well. Weekends tend to be workdays to some extent after starting a full-time job post self-employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my nerd highlight of the weekend was -finally- getting Ubuntu onto my Chromebook. Afterward it essentially turns into a dualboot system (kind of), but one much more robust. For the purists that believe that a Chromebook is meant to remain a simple, Google-powered netbook - where&amp;rsquo;s the fun in that?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my Samsung Chromebook (ARM) I pressed Esc+Refresh+Power to cycle into Developer Mode. Wait a moment. Press Enter. Then, wait for it to delete your local files (which you&amp;rsquo;ll want to back up beforehand) before booting into what looks like a fresh Chrome OS environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is, now you are able to type Ctrl+Alt+T to bring up a Terminal &lt;del&gt;window&lt;/del&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/fd3zc&quot;&gt;install crouton&lt;/a&gt; and leave it in your Downloads folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I wanted to install Ubuntu 14.04 Trusty. Both my Windows machine at home and my machine at work are running 12.04 Precise. Old, buggy, yet familiar. In with the new (and stable)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That takes you into a shell environment where you are able to tinker to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content. (Careful, don&amp;rsquo;t break anything&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ sudo sh -e ~/Downloads/crouton -r trusty -t xfce,chromium
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The xfce desktop is fugly at best but that&amp;rsquo;s what themes are for. We&amp;rsquo;re kind of limited with 14.04 on the ARM Chromebook. No Unity. (I tried both Unity and Gnome to no avail before reading that xfce was our best bet on an ARM Chromebook.) And naturally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to have Chromium installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, my installation was underway and at that point I took a shower and did my makeup while letting it finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I returned it asked for a username and password. Success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterward, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to enter your chroot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ sudo enter-chroot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then start your Linux environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ startxfce4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace xfce4 with whichever target environment you chose to switch into your [Trusty] new Linux environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiffy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/06/16/trusty-install-chromebook/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/06/16/trusty-install-chromebook/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's Friday...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday the 13th&lt;/strong&gt;, for that matter. Not that that matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m testing out &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; blogging from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gives me a satisfaction nostalgic of learning how to code Greymatter CGI for the first time, when I started blogging back in 2001 or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get Jekyll to work right away. The website promised it would be easy. Not so, not for me. Yes, Mercury is currently retrograde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most satisfactory commands that worked today, separately, were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ rvm implode
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Me deciding rvm was absolutely worthless.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I compiled Ruby from source, and magically all my problems dissolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ sudo gem install jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yess! Success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In case the SEO bots catch on, I searched relentlessly for a fix to the &lt;em&gt;zlib loaderror&lt;/em&gt; I kept running into using &amp;lsquo;gem install&amp;rsquo;. So, I had rvm go screw itself then compiled Ruby manually. This installed all dependencies and fixed everything.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2014/06/13/its-friday-13th/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2014/06/13/its-friday-13th/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>